RG 004:102, North Stonington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
North Stonington Probate Court records
1835-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (North Stonington District)
12 cubic feet
Record books, 1835-1970; Probate files, 1835-1912; Wills, 1907-1976
RG004_102
1923-005, 2011-051, 2011-107
Historical Note
North Stonington, New London, Town established in May 1807, Parent Town: Stonington
The North Stonington Probate District was constituted June 4, 1835, from the Stonington Probate District. The North Stonington Probate District merged with Groton, Ledyard, and Stonington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Southeastern Corner Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Groton, Ledyard, North Stonington, and Stonington.
Town of North Stonington, Probate District chronology:
May 1807 - June 3, 1835, Stonington District
June 4, 1835 - January 4, 2011, North Stonington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Southeastern Corner Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1835-1970. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 7. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1835-1912. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1835-1912 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Wills, 1907-1976.
Arrangement
There are two series of record books, Records and Journals. Both are numbered 1-7.
Probate files in accession 1923-005 are arranged alphabetically.
Wills in accession 2011-107 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1923-005 are represented in this index.
Wills: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-107.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- North Stonington
Places:
North Stonington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-051, Record books, 1835-1970, and Accession 2011-107, Wills, 1907-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 1835-1933 and journals, volumes 1-5, 1835-1937 probate files, 1835-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1923-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 23, 1923 (1835-1912).
The record books in accession 2011-051 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 22, 2010.
The probate wills in accession 2011-107 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 31, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1835-1970; 9 cubic feet (14 volumes); 2011-051
  - Records, 1835-1858 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1858-1893 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1890-1905 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1905-1913 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1915-1933 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1933-1955 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1955-1980 (Volume 7)
  - Journal, 1835-1852 (Volume 1)
  - Journal, 1853-1873 (Volume 2)
  - Journal, 1873-1898 (Volume 3)
  - Journal, 1898-1913 (Volume 4)
  - Journal, 1913-1937 (Volume 5)
  - Journal, 1925-1963 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1964-1969 (Volume 7)
- Probate files, 1835-1912; 2 cubic feet; 1923-005
  - Allen - Congdon (Drawer 1)
  - Coon - Main (Drawer 2)
  - Mallory - Wheeler, E. (Drawer 3)
  - Wheeler, F. - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 4)
- Inventory Control Book, 1835-1912; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1923-005
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Wills, 1907-1976; 1 cubic foot; 2011-107
  - A-Z (Box 1)